Lior Gonnen

Software Engineer at Facebook

Summary

Entrepreneur. Passionate about designing and building mass-market products. I'm a product person with full-stack software engineering and architecture background and experience.

Programming has been my passion and hobby long before it became a profession. I see it as a form of art, visualizing and creating something out of nothing, with endless attention to the smallest of details.

Nowadays it's one tool among many others that allow me to bootstrap any idea, no matter how big.

But a company is as good as the people it's made of, and it takes at least two people to brainstorm.

If you're an awesome person, and you want to build something big. Let's talk.

Experience

Software Engineer at Facebook

November 2015 - Present

Founder and CEO at Roundup

April 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Roundup is an instant news reader, aggregating tech-news articles from your twitter and other RSS feeds to create a personalized news collection for a clean, beautiful and effortless reading-experience.

The home-page is dead. Many of us get most of our news on Facebook, Twitter and other social networks. The news you care about is already there, but it gets hard to separate news pieces from social posts, friend updates and promotions and find the news that actually matter and interest us. Roundup does the heavy lifting for you, and lets you catch up on news you care about from people that matter - in a beautiful, effortless, noise free reading experience.

Co-founder at Wivi SMS (formerly invi)

February 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 11 months)

Wivi SMS (formerly invi) was meant to become the next generation of texting. Letting you communicate via free messaging, SMS or Google Voice - making your conversations beautiful and engaging. Any kind of content such as articles, photos and YouTube videos is automatically embedded into the chat.

Co-founder and CTO

January 2012 - December 2012 (1 year)

The Asthma Monitor is a low-cost, mobile-health, Asthma monitoring system to automate disease management. It includes a simple device that connects to the smartphone via bluetooth and is equivalent to a medical spirometer and can predict an Asthma attack 3 days ahead and help regulate long-term medication.

- # Designed and built a prototype of the Android client that allows the Asthma patient to measure their respiratory parameters and automatically transfer them to online PHR's Google Health and Microsoft HealthVault.
- # Awarded Israeli Chief Scientist's Tnufa grant of \$200K.
- # Patent-pending technology for a "Modular acoustic spirometer".

Founder

August 2009 - February 2012 (2 years 7 months)

I started developing apps for Google's Android platform as soon as the platform became public.

Wave Launcher was one of the 10 grossing paid apps at the end of 2011 at was one of the 0.02% paid-apps to cross the 50K downloads barrier.

Wave launcher had a great marketing gimmick - Bringing the beloved WebOS feature to Android, and was one of the first apps (if not the very first) that utilized UI that can appear on top of any other app.

Both UltimateFaves and Awesome! Notifier use an in-house OpenGL engine for graphics.

Awesome! Notifer had just a single release after which I moved to Silicon Valley to start invi.

Software Team Leader at SAE Afikim

December 2007 - June 2009 (1 year 7 months)

Led a team of 4 engineers covering all client-side architecture, design and implementation.

Software Engineer at SAE Afikim

August 2006 - June 2009 (2 years 11 months)

- # Designed and led the client side implementation of next generation AfiFarm, a web-based herd management system.
- # Researched and tested new and existing technologies, choosing the ones to be used for product development.
- # Designed and developed a JavaScript and C# Ajax framework that turns every ASP.NET application into an Ajax application by replacing the native postback mechanism.
- # Main technologies used: Adobe Flex, ActionScript 3, ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server.

Software Engineer at GE Healthcare

February 2002 - July 2006 (4 years 6 months)

- # Owned key C++/Java development roles of the company's core medical scanner platform.
- # Designed and developed a framework for a real-time ECG display supporting several types of headless ECG devices, thus reducing the production cost of each nuclear scanner by \$3000.
- # Initiated the project of fully-automated software installation on host-PC and medical scanner, and single-handedly implemented a complex multi-machine InstallShield script reducing installation time by 40%.

Education

University of Haifa

B.Sc, Computer Science, 2002 - 2007

Lior Gonnen

Software Engineer at Facebook



Contact Lior on LinkedIn